Everybody gotta have a dream.
Hustle & Flow is a crime, drama, music film directed by Craig Brewer.
With help from his friends, a Memphis pimp in a mid-life crisis
attempts to become a successful hip-hop emcee.
Djay, played by Terrence Howard.
Key, played by Anthony Anderson.
Nola, played by Taryn Manning.
Shug, played by Taraji P. Henson.
Shelby, played by DJ Qualls.
Skinny Black, played by Ludacris.
Hustle & Flow is a 2005 American drama film
written and directed by Craig Brewer.
The film stars Terrence Howard as a Memphis hustler and
pimp who dreams of becoming a rapper.
The ensemble cast includes Anthony Anderson, Taryn Manning, Taraji P.
Henson, Paula Jai Parker, Elise Neal, DJ Qualls and Ludacris.
Produced by John Singleton and Stephanie Allain, the film tells the story of
one man's struggle to turn his life around through music.
Hustle & Flow was released on July 22, 2005, by Paramount Classics, and received positive reviews from critics, who praised the
performances—particularly those of Howard and Henson—as well as Brewer's direction and the film's soundtrack.
The film emerged as a commercial success at the box-office, grossing
$23.5 million against a production budget of $2.8 million.
Hustle & Flow garnered several accolades, including two nominations at the 78th Academy Awards: Best Actor (Howard) and Best Original Song for Three 6 Mafia's song "It's Hard
out Here for a Pimp", winning the latter, thus becoming the second hip-hop song to win an Academy Award, following Eminem's "Lose Yourself" from 8 Mile (2002).
The film explores themes of drug dealer, career, baby, rap music, hip-hop.
The tone is emotional.